MAX BUNGAY

FRONT END DEVELOPER

CONTACT



https://github.com/max-b10



linkedin.com/in/max-bungay



bungaymax@gmail.com



+44 7580 021696

PROFILE

I am a driven and competitive individual with 2+ years of experience as a front end developer and mobile app developer at a property management software company. I successfully transitioned my career into software development after teaching myself the necessary fundamental skills during the Covid-19 pandemic. Over the last 2 years as a professional software engineer, I have continued learning and improving my knowledge and skills. I have gained hands-on experience with React/Next.js on the company's project of creating a new and improved version of the existing legacy web application as a frontend developer. Additionally, I have been an active member of the mobile app team utilising Xamarin/C# and Ionic/Angular.

SKILLS

JavaScript

Typescript

HTML / CSS / SCSS

React

Jest (Unit testing)

Client-side API Integration

Fetch and Axios

TSX (TypeScript JSX)

Angular

Next.js

PrimeReact

Storybook

Ionic SDK

Bootstrap

Jira | Atlassian

C# / XAML

Xamarin

iOS app development

Android app development

Git version control

GitHub

Bitbucket

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer

Arthur Online | Jan 2023 – present

Arthur is a property management software company with a range of software designed to aid clients in the property space such as: tenants, contractors, property managers and property owners.

I am responsible for the front end development of an entirely new version of the existing legacy system, alongside one other front end developer,

Activity associated with this role:

- Utilise React with TypeScript and Next.js to modernise and enhance the system's functionality and user interface.
- Develop reusable and efficient React components, leveraging the PrimeReact UI
 component library and Storybook to create interactive user interfaces.
- Use the React Hook Forms library to optimise form management, enhancing data input, validation and user interaction.
- Utilise the fetch API and Axios library to communicate with the API developed by the backend team, enabling seamless data retrieval and manipulation on the frontend.
- Actively initiated learning unit testing methodologies, including the use of Jest.
- Engage actively in Agile sprints alongside my team of developers, designers and QA
 personnel delivering software solutions to meet deadlines.
- Collaborate closely with designers on the feasibility and practicality of their Figma designs.
- Employ Git and GitHub for code collaboration, overseeing version control, pull requests and code reviews.

EDUCATION

BSc (HONS) PSYCHOLOGY -UPPER SECOND CLASS NOTTINGHAM TRENT UNIVERSITY

LONG ROAD SIXTH FORM COLLEGE

ST EDMUND'S SCHOOL, CANTERBURY

INTERESTS

Consumer Behaviour

User Experience

Psychology

Russian Literature

Sport

Chess

OTHER

Store Assistant, Scotsdales Garden Centre

Night Colleague, ASDA (Nottingham)

Sports Scholarship, St Edmund's School Canterbury

Represented Kent County in Football, Hockey and Cricket as a junior

Nottingham Trent University $\mathbf{1}^{\text{st}}$ XI Football

REFERENCES

Paolo Ursino CTO Arthur Online T: +44 7974 111004

T: +44 7974 111004 E: kirsty@crowdcat.co

Kirsty Davis Manager CrowdCat

T: +44 7974 111004 E: kirsty@crowdcat.co

WORK EXPERIENCE - CONTINUED

Mobile App Developer

Arthur Online | June 2021 - Jan 2023

I was responsible for the maintenance, improvement and building of the company's apps, including their deployment to the Apple and Google Play stores.

Activity associated with this role:

- Utilised the *Ionic SDK* with *Angular* and *Typescript* to work on and deploy cross-platform
 apps to the Apple and Google Play stores.
- Utilised the Xamarin.Forms framework written in XAML and C# to work on and deploy crossplatform apps to the Apple and Google Play stores.
- Consider responsive design to ensure the apps are suitable for all screen sizes, including larger devices for the Progressive Web App (PWA) versions.
- Bug fixing and feature requests.
- Communicate with back-end developers to discuss API alterations and additions.

Notable work:

- Take responsibility alongside one other team member for the maintenance and deployment
 of 3 cross-platform Ionic apps used by thousands of users across the Apple and Google Play
 stores.
- Completed a re-write of the Tenant mobile app using Xamarin.Forms, previously written with Ionic.
- Developed and maintained several bespoke, cross-platform lonic apps for various clients.

Covid-19 Pandemic

Self-taught software development | November 2020 - May 2021

Activity:

- Focused on learning Html, CSS and vanilla JavaScript.
- Used netlify.com to build and deploy my portfolio: https://portfoliomax.netlify.app/.

Digital Account Executive

CrowdCat | October 2018 - October 2020

CrowdCat is a data-driven marketing and psychometrics company. As a digital account executive, my focus was on the support and management of a bespoke Content Management System (*CMS*) alongside a team of software engineers.

Activity associated with this job role:

- Worked very closely with the software development team to maintain and consistently improve the *CMS* being used by the clients.
- Organise and keep track of the *Jira* workflow for the software development team.
- Identified and fixed CSS styling issues within the digital promotions of the CMS.